Guide to the Ian P. Watt Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2000-166
  - Vineberg, Steve. "On Filming Conrad: Outcast of the Islands, Razumov, and Sabotage" (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Warren, Robert Penn. "Nostromo". (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Watt: Articles (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Watt. "Biographical Summary" (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Watt: Course Notes, the Enlightenment (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Watt: Humanities on the Kwai (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Watt. Joseph Conrad: Nostromo. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Watt, note, 2/10/89 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Watt: Notes to Self (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Watt on Irony (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Watt: On Mind in Fiction (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Watt: On the Kwai as Myth (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Watt. "Reunion on the Kwai" (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Watt: The Decline of the Decline (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Watt "The Liberty of the Prison" (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Watt: The Secret Sharer (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Watts, Cedric (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Winnepeg Paper (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Writing about Conrad: Early Versions (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - "B" Articles (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "D" Articles (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - "E" Articles (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - "F" Articles (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - "G" Articles (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "H" Articles (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "K" Articles (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "L" Articles (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - "M" Articles (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "N" Articles (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - "P" Articles (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - "R" Articles (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "S" Articles (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - "T" Articles (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - "U" Articles (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - "V" Articles (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - "W" Articles (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2002-199
  Box 1 of this accession pertains to Watt's research on three works by Joseph Conrad: Chance, The Secret Agent, and Typhoon
  - Chance – notes, sources (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chance – MLA paper (mss.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chance – MLA correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Secret Agent – articles, notes, and miscellany, 1959-86 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Secret Agent – correspondence, 1971-86 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Secret Agent – sources (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Secret Agent – papers by Jim English, 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Secret Agent – student papers (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Typhoon – drafts Aug. 26, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Typhoon – drafts Oct. 30, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Typhoon – drafts Nov. 8, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Typhoon – drafts Nov. 10, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Typhoon – drafts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Typhoon – drafts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Typhoon – notes and a draft (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Typhoon – miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Typhoon – sources re (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Typhoon – Whiting (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Typhoon – Whiting (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Typhoon – Whiting (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Conrad – miscellaneous notes (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - End of the tether [Watt's title] – first page of newsletter Joseph Conrad Today, July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Johnson, Bruce, "Joseph Conrad: A Study in the Philosophy of Metaphor" (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Watt, Ian – miscellany, including biography and bibliography (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Photograph album on the occasion of Watt's retirement as head of the Stanford Humanities Center in 1985 (Box 2)
    - Photographs, poetry, letters and notes, and brochures of Center events (Box 2)